

□ (626)688-5517 | ☑ jhuan126@ucr.edu | ☑ janinehuang | ὧ janine-huang

Summary_

Software Engineer, Full Stack Developer, and Honors Computer Science student with 3+ years of experience. Engaged, creative third-year student eager to learn; Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

Programming Languages: C++, Python, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS Technology: Git, Unix, Flask, AWS, Virtual Reality, React Leadership: Public Speaking, Project and Team Management, Integrity

Work Experience _____

Rose Hack Riverside, California

LEAD DEVELOPER July 2018 - Feb. 2019

- Lead engineer on official event website that can save user entered applications and send live updates with React and Gatsby
- Interfaced with form submission and design software to expedite user data collection for over 270+ applications
- Trained 50+ undergraduates to be proficient with relevant web technologies

University of California, Riverside

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Riverside, California

June 2018 - July 2018

- Implemented file readers/writers for JSON inputs/outputs to match system architecture properties
- Refactor large components of code to adapt to new libraries and class structures
- Implemented a continuous status flag printing system to expedite debugging, testing, and readability

ASSISTANT INSTRUCTOR

June 2018 - July 2018

- Mentor and coach secondary school students in introductory Python and Android development
- · Construct programming demonstrations to showcase basic console output, class structure, and functions
- 100+ deployable first-time programmer student projects

Projects_____

FireWatch

MAR. 2019

• Web application that highlights increased fire risk areas on a California. created with machine learning algorithm and Google Cloud's Maps API.

C++ Terminal

MAR. 2019

• Implemented a simple command shell from scratch in C++ to allow basic command execution. Allows users to chain commands with precedence and piping

CitrusTrack

MAR. 2018

• Web application that structures and manages a user's tasks with task timers. Supports mobile interfaces. 2nd place winner in UI/UX.

Extracurricular Activity _____

ACM@UCR Riverside, California

CHAIR, SECRETARY

Mar. 2018 - PRESENT

Mul. 2010 T NESENT

- Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building networks on and off campus by strengthening student and faculty bonds
 Optimized team management to handle drastic growth in member involvement following our Citrus Hack, UCR's 350+ attendee hackathon
- · Mentored and Trained the next generation of software engineering leaders in professional, academic, and technical development

Education

University of California, Riverside

Riverside, California

Sept. 2017 - Present

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Cumultative GPA: 3.31
- Dean's Honor List, 2 Years in University Honors